workopolis.com 2017-01-29

# Workopolis Privacy Policy - About

_Last Updated on September 10, 2015_

At the Workopolis Partnership (‘ **Workopolis** ‘), protecting your privacy is very important to us. Workopolis treats your personal information with the utmost respect and in accordance with this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy explains how personal information, about you, may be collected, used, or disclosed as a consequence of your activities on the Workopolis website. We urge you to read it carefully. By registering on this site, by submitting your resume or any information through the use of this site, or by otherwise accessing this site or using any of our services, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and consent to the policies and practices described for the collection, use or disclosure of personal information.

  * Protection of Personal Information
  * What Information Do We Collect
  * Use of Information by Workopolis
  * Retention of Information
  * Your Consent
  * Disclosure of Information
  * Access and Accuracy and Update of Personal Information
  * Safeguards
  * Changes to Workpolis Privacy Policy
  * Co-Branded and Other Associated sites
  * Contact Us

#### Protection of Personal Information

  1. Canadian law governs the collection, use and disclosure of personal information in a manner that recognizes individuals’ right of privacy with respect to their personal information.
  2. The federal Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (‘ **PIPEDA** ‘) sets out rules and principles for the management of personal information by commercial organizations. Workopolis services are made available to employers and job seekers across Canada. PIPEDA applies to Workopolis because it is an organization headquartered in Ontario, Canada.
  3. The type of personal information that is protected includes almost any information about an identifiable individual, such as your name, address, telephone number, age, sex, marital status and nationality. Personal information may not, however, include certain types of business or employment related information. It does not, for example, include the name, title, business address or telephone number of an employee of an organization. Information contained in resumés that you elect to post to this site may constitute personal information and would be subject to this Privacy Policy.
  4. PIPEDA provides certain fundamental principles which apply to the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information. One of the most significant, is that your personal information generally cannot be collected, used or disclosed without your consent. It also allows you to find out why your personal information is being collected, how it is being used, where it’s being stored and to whom it’s disclosed. It requires the use of appropriate safeguards to secure your personal information. It also grants you access to your personal information and provides mechanisms for ensuring compliance.
  5. Workopolis does not collect, use or disclose your personal information without your consent except where required or allowed by law.

#### What Information Do We Collect

  1. Workopolis limits the collection of your personal information to that which is required or permitted by law. Workopolis collects such personal information as is required for the purposes identified in this Privacy Policy or identified by Workopolis at the time that we collect the information from you.
  2. Workopolis requests certain information from you if you elect to register as a user of this site (‘ **Registration Information** ‘). Registration Information includes your full name, email address and postal code.
  3. If you are a registered user of the site, you may elect to post one or more resumés (‘ **Resumés** ‘) to the site. The extent of the information that is collected when you post a Resumé depends on what you choose to place in your Resumé. At a minimum, if you post a Resumé, Workopolis will require that you provide your full name, postal code, phone number and email address. Your Resumé may contain additional information such as your experience, education, skills or any other information about yourself that you decide to provide.
  4. At times, Workopolis may ask you to provide general information about yourself to assist us in meeting your various needs or to better understand the requirements, profiles and experience of our site visitors. Workopolis may also ask you to provide or allow us access to specific information about you, contained on other databases. This information includes: information that is collected if you choose to participate in a survey; if you ask to be kept updated about new developments, services or features offered by Workopolis or its business partners; if you utilize any of our services or features; or if you contact Workopolis. All of the information in this paragraph is referred to in this Privacy Policy as ‘ **User Information** ‘.
  5. You can visit this site without telling us who you are and without providing Workopolis with any information about yourself. However, certain anonymous information (‘ **Anonymous Information** ‘) may be collected automatically as you navigate through the site or use our services, including usage details, sites visited prior to visiting our site, IP addresses and information collected through cookies, web beacons and other tracking technologies. Please note that portions of this site will not function if you do not accept cookies.
  6. With the exception of the Anonymous Information described above, you will always know when we are collecting information from you and therefore have the opportunity not to provide the information.
  7. The purposes for which Workopolis collects any information will always be as set out in this Privacy Policy or as otherwise expressly communicated to you before we collect the information.
  8. Some ads appearing on this website are delivered to you by DoubleClick, a web advertising company. Information about your visits to this site, such as the number of times you have viewed an ad (but not your name, address or other personal information) is used to serve additional ads to you. For more information about DoubleClick, cookies, and how to ‘opt-out’, please visit <http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/index.aspx>

#### Use of Information by Workopolis

##### Registration Information

  1. **Registration Information** is collected primarily for the purpose of identifying you as a user of this site.

##### User Information

  2. **User Information** , which generally includes the **Registration Information** , is used primarily to update you on the site, and to email you regarding new site developments and information about our services or those of our affiliates, to answer your questions, and to provide you with services that you have requested.
  3. **User Information** may also be used to determine appropriate new features, content or services for this site, to permit Workopolis or its business partners to contact you in a more specific and focused manner depending on the content of your **User Information** , or to provide advertisers and business partners with aggregate but not personally identifiable information about our customers and their preferences, including statistical information about the source of visitors, sales, traffic patterns and use of services.
  4. If you are a registered user of this site and have provided Workopolis with **Registration Information** , we may use your **Registration Information** and **User Information** to provide tailored job opportunities or other information to you.

##### Anonymous Information

  5. **Anonymous Information** is used primarily by us and our business partners to measure the number of visits, average time spent, page views, and other statistics about visitors to this site. Workopolis may also use this data to monitor site performance for systems administration purposes, to make this site and some of our services easier and more convenient to use, for law enforcement purposes, and to share information in aggregate but not personally identifiable form with our advertisers and business partners.
  6. If cookies are enabled for your internet browser, then they are used to help us measure the number of visits, average time spent, page views, and other statistics relating to your use of this site. If you are performing a search on our site, then a cookie is used to carry the search request data from the request page to the results page. This cookie, by itself, does not tell us your email address or who you are.
  7. If Workopolis uses your **Registration Information** and **User Information** to provide tailored job opportunities or other information to you, we use cookies to recognize you on subsequent visits to our site and to make your on-line experience more convenient.
  8. **Anonymous Information** may be used to serve you with targeted advertising or tailored job advertisements on this site. Targeted advertisements and tailored job advertisements maybe be more interesting for you and are more productive for our advertisers and employers. While Workopolis does not collect personal information automatically, if you are using the site as a **Registered User** we may tie this information to personal information about you that we collect from other sources or you provide to us.

##### Resumés

  9. **Resumés** are accessed by employers, recruiters, human resource professionals and other registered users of the Workopolis Resumé database. You will be provided with the choice of either allowing all parties who use our **Resumé** database service to access your **Resumé** and to contact you, or of limiting access to those organizations to whom you choose to apply for a job.
  10. Workopolis makes every effort through contractual means and through the use of user IDs and passwords to restrict those who have access to our **Resumé** database from using **Resumés** other than for the purpose of fulfilling a job posting. However, Workopolis cannot guarantee that all employers, recruiters and other persons with access will adhere to the limitations that Workopolis imposes on them, or that unauthorized persons will not gain access to the database. If at any time you would like your Resumé removed from the Workopolis site, you may do so by using the ‘ **Delete Resumé** ‘ function located on the site. However, employers, recruiters and others who have subscribed for access to the **Resumé** database, or for whose job posting you may have applied, may already have retained a copy of your **Resumé** in their own systems and databases.
  11. Some job postings which are posted on this site allow you to follow links to other sites where you can apply for specific job postings or submit your **Resumé**. In some cases these sites are co-branded with the sites of employers, human resources customers or with the sites of our business partners. In some cases, such sites are still within the control of the Workopolis web server. 

Any **Resumé** or other information of any kind that you provide, including as a part of a job application process, is outside the control of Workopolis and its web servers. In such cases, you will be providing your **Resumé** directly to the employer, recruiter, human resources professional or other person, and your **Resumé** will be subject to their practices and their privacy policies or practices. Workopolis is not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of such third parties. In such cases, we encourage you to review the third party’s privacy policy.

  12. In addition to the provisions of the Workopolis Privacy Policy, the collection, use and disclosure of your **Resumé** is governed by the terms and conditions of use of this site, a copy of which can be obtained from the home page of this site.

##### Surveys

  13. When information is collected from you by Workopolis as a part of an online or email survey, unless you request to receive the results of the survey, no personally identifiable information is requested during such surveys and all collected information is used on an aggregated basis only.

##### Communication with Workopolis

  14. If you contact Workopolis, we may keep a record of the correspondence but we do not make any use of the email address or other contact information, other than to respond to the communication.

##### Improper Use of Personal Information

  15. Although Workopolis uses all reasonable means to ensure that the information you provide to us is not used by third parties for purposes other than those described in this Privacy Policy, Workopolis is not responsible for any improper use of your personal information that is beyond our reasonable control.

#### Retention of Information

  1. You may choose to delete your **Resumé** from our Workopolis records at any time. We also delete **Resumés** from our records in accordance with internally developed experience criteria based upon when your **Resumé** was created, last edited or last used to apply for a job posting, as well as your use of your account. Certain Registration Information regarding your account with us will normally be retained such as your name, email address and postal code should you wish to post a **Resumé** or access our services subsequently.
  2. We maintain record retention practices and policies which apply to personal information that is no longer necessary or relevant for the identified purposes, or that is no longer required or permitted by law to be retained.
  3. As a part of the Workopolis record retention practices and policies, you may request deletion of your personal information by contacting us using this contact form, selecting ‘ **Privacy Policy** ‘ from the ‘ **I have a question regarding** ‘ drop-down menu and filling in your request in the ‘ **Detail** s’ section of the contact form; we will erase all of your personal information upon request, including your **Registration Information** and account. If personal information is ever to be used to make a decision it will be retained long enough to allow you access to the information after the decision has been made.
  4. All personal information destroyed or erased from our records is done so securely with due regard to the sensitivity of the information.

#### Your Consent

  1. Workopolis does not collect, use or disclose your personal information without your consent except where required or permitted by law.
  2. Workopolis may, for example, collect, use or disclose personal information without your knowledge or consent in the case of an emergency where the life, health or security of an individual is threatened.
  3. Workopolis may also disclose personal information without knowledge or consent to a lawyer or other advisor representing Workopolis, to collect a debt, to comply with a subpoena, warrant or other court order or rules, is required for the investigation or enforcement of laws, or as may otherwise be required or authorized by law. Where a request for personal information is made by an organization claiming lawful authority for the request, Workopolis will take reasonable steps to ensure that the requesting party properly identifies its legal authority.
  4. Workopolis will generally obtain your consent electronically on our site. However, it may also be obtained in writing or verbally. In determining the appropriate form of consent, we will consider the sensitivity of and reasonable expectations regarding the personal information.
  5. Workopolis will not require you to consent to the collection, use or disclosure of personal information as a condition to the supply of any products or services, except to the extent reasonably required to fulfill the purposes identified in this Privacy Policy or otherwise identified at the time that we collect your personal information.
  6. You may withdraw your consent to the continued collection, use or disclosure of your personal information by Workopolis at any time by using this contact form, selecting ‘ **Privacy Policy** ‘ from the ‘ **I have a question regarding** ‘ drop-down menu and filling in your request in the ‘ **Details** ‘ section of the contact form, or by calling **1-888-641-4047** , but such a request would be subject to legal or contractual restrictions. We would also require reasonable advance notice to effect any requested changes. A request that Workopolis no longer collect or use your **Registration Information** or certain **User Information** or **Anonymous Information** , may mean that we will no longer have practical means to provide you with our services or products. You may no longer be able to log in to our site or may lose certain functionality when visiting the site, including functionality that depends on **Anonymous Information** such as the placement of cookies.
  7. If you withdraw your consent to the disclosure of personal information that you have previously authorized Workopolis to share with others, such as your **Resumé** , you should know that employers, recruiters and others who have subscribed to the **Resumé** database or for whose job posting you may have applied, may already have retained a copy of your **Resumé** or such personal information in their own systems and databases.

#### Disclosure of Information

  1. Workopolis will not sell, trade, rent or license personal information that you provide to us.
  2. Workopolis uses domestic and foreign third party service providers to host and process certain data, including **Resumés** for **Resumé** database search functionality, and credit card transactions if employers, recruiters or others have subscribed for access to paid services such as the **Resumé** database. Third party service providers are required to comply with privacy laws and principles comparable to ours.
  3. Workopolis may disclose your personal information to third parties who acquire all or a substantial part of the Workopolis business, including by merger, amalgamation, a sale of our assets or in the unlikely event of bankruptcy. Subject to a court order, at the time of such merger, amalgamation, sale or bankruptcy, Workopolis would contractually require any resulting entity that obtains your personal information to comply with its obligations under PIPEDA regarding your personal information, including the applicable terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy.

#### Access and Accuracy and Update of Personal Information

  1. Workopolis will take reasonable steps to ensure that your personal information is as accurate, complete and up-to-date as is appropriate for its purposes and to minimize the possibility that inappropriate information may be used to make a decision about you.
  2. Workopolis provides you with the means to access, update, edit or delete **Registration Information** and certain other personal information you have provided to us at any time on your own by going to My Workopolis on the site and changing or deleting your **Registration Information** and other personal information as desired. We ask that you regularly log in to the site and update your personal information and in particular your contact information to ensure its accuracy.
  3. You can update or delete your **Resumé** at any time by logging on to the site and making the required changes. However, employers, recruiters and others who subscribe to the **Resumé** database or for whose job posting you may have applied, may already have retained a copy of your **Resumé** in their own systems and databases.
  4. You may similarly contact us to address errors or omissions relating to your personal information by using this contact form, selecting ‘Privacy Policy’ from the ‘I have a question regarding’ drop-down menu and filling in your request in the ‘ **Details** ‘ section of the [contact form](http://www.workopolis.com/shared/en/contactus/seeker), or by telephoning **1-888-641-4047**. Workopolis does not share your identifiable personal information with any third party.
  5. If you decide at any time that you do not want to receive any updates to which you have subscribed, you can log in to the site and change your personal preferences, or you can contact us using this contact form, selecting ‘ **Privacy Policy** ‘ from the ‘ **I have a question regarding** ‘ drop-down menu and filling in your request in the ‘ **Details** ‘ section of the [contact form](http://www.workopolis.com/shared/en/contactus/seeker), indicating your preference not to receive updates.
  6. Upon request made in writing, Workopolis will inform you of the existence, use and disclosure of your personal information, at minimal or no cost to you, in accordance with processes and procedures that we have put in place for such requests. If you are unsure whether we have a record containing your personal information and would like to confirm what personal information we have, please send your request using this [contact form](http://www.workopolis.com/shared/en/contactus/seeker), selecting ‘ **Privacy Policy** ‘ from the ‘ **I have a question regarding** ‘ drop-down menu and filling in your request in the ‘ **Details** ‘ section of the contact form, identifying all email addresses which you may have given to Workopolis. If there is a cost involved at all, we will inform you at that time.
  7. Workopolis may require additional information from you in order to verify your identity following an access request. Such personal information will only be used for the purpose of identity verification and will itself be subject to protection under the terms of this Privacy Policy.
  8. Workopolis will respond to all requests for access within 30 days or as otherwise required or permitted by law.
  9. In some circumstances, we may not be able to provide access to all of the personal information that we hold about you. Workopolis may not provide access to information if doing so would likely reveal personal information about a third party, could be expected to threaten the life or security of an individual, reveal confidential commercial information, if the information is protected by a legally recognized privilege, if it was created as part of a settlement or dispute resolution process, or if it was collected in relation to the investigation of a breach of an agreement or a contravention of law. Workopolis will provide the reasons to you if it refuses an access request.
  10. An individual shall be able to challenge the accuracy and completeness of their information and have it amended as appropriate.

#### Safeguards

  1. Where Workopolis considers it appropriate, having due regard to the sensitivity of the particular information that we collect, use or disclose, Workopolis uses encryption or authentication tools, among other methods, practices and procedures, to protect your personal information irrespective of which format it is stored in. Our practices and procedures for safeguarding your information are regularly reviewed.
  2. E-mails you send to Workopolis are not necessarily secure when they are transmitted to us. If your communication is sensitive or includes confidential information you must provide it instead via by telephone or by post. If your communication includes a credit card number you must contact Workopolis by phone at **1-888-641-4047** extension 3.
  3. It is important that you keep your user ID and password information secure and that you not share it with anyone, in order to safeguard your personal information on our Workopolis site.
  4. There are occasionally fraudulent ‘phishing’ emails targeting individuals who the perpetrators believe might be registered users of this site. Workopolis never sends an email that requests users to visit a webpage or place a call to provide their user ID, password or any personal information. We will never ask you to confirm your user ID or password via email. If you ever receive such an email, do not log in from any referred link and do not provide any personal information. You should contact our Business Support Group at 1-888-641-4047 immediately and inform us of the email.
  5. Workopolis works to protect the security of credit card information during transmission by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts information you input. Workopolis does not reveal credit card numbers when confirming an order. 
  6. Our employees receive regular privacy training. Employees are instructed to only use personal information in adherence with the principles set forth in this Privacy Policy and the laws applicable to each specific business. The only employees who have access to your personal information are administrative personnel. Employees who misuse customer personal information may be subject to disciplinary action.

#### Changes to Our Privacy Policy 

  1. Workopolis reserves the right to modify or supplement this Privacy Policy statement at any time. If we make any material change to this Privacy Policy, we will update this site to include such changes and post a notice on our home page, for a period of 30 days, with a link to the updated Privacy Policy. Please read any such notice and the new policy statement. If you return to this site after a period of more than 30 days, please check this Privacy Policy to confirm that you are aware of the details of the most recent update. Please look at the top of this Privacy Policy to check the date that it was updated and to confirm that you are familiar with the terms of the most recent update. Your continued use of this site after we post such notice will constitute your acceptance of the new terms and their application to your use of this site and the personal information disclosed for such use, including personal information previously furnished us, as if they were the initial terms, and your consent to the use of your personal information as described in this privacy policy and elsewhere on our website.
  2. Workopolis will always seek your consent if we want to use your personal information for purposes other than for those set out in this Privacy Policy or to which you have previously agreed.

#### Co-Branded and Other Associated sites

  1. Workopolis has partnered with reputable third parties to offer our customers a variety of services. Many of these services also require registration to make them function properly. You can recognize most of these sites if you see both organizations’ names on the webpage. For example, if you see a logo on the page that says ‘Powered by’, you are on a co-hosted site. We also have other third-party relationships, where the third party provides the technology or service under the Workopolis name and website. In either of these cases, unless otherwise indicated at the registration page, Workopolis does not provide your Registration Information to its third party business partners. Although we only work with reputable third parties, our third party business partners may have different privacy policies and practices than Workopolis. We encourage you to review our business partners’ privacy policies further to understand their procedures for collecting, using and disclosing personal information.
  2. The Workopolis site may contain links to other sites, including those of our business partners, vendors and advertisers. While we try to link only to sites that share our high standards and respect for privacy, please understand that we are not responsible for the content of, or the privacy practices employed by, other sites.

#### Contact Us

  1. Workopolis will make information about its policies and practices relating to management of personal information readily available. Please direct any questions about our privacy policies and procedures, any requests for access to our records of your personal information and any other privacy related concerns or complaints using this [contact form](http://www.workopolis.com/shared/en/contactus/seeker), selecting ‘ **Privacy Policy** ‘ from the ‘ **I have a question regarding** ‘ drop-down menu, and filling in your request in the ‘ **Details** ‘ section of the contact form. All privacy related complaints will be acknowledged, recorded, investigated and responded to in accordance with applicable law.
  2. You can contact us by using this [contact form](http://www.workopolis.com/shared/en/contactus/seeker), selecting ‘ **Privacy Policy** ‘ from the ‘ **I have a question regarding** ‘ drop-down menu, and filling in your request in the ‘ **Details** ‘ section of the form, through our toll-free line at **1-888-641-4047** , or by postal mail to: **Workopolis Privacy Officer, 720 King Street West, 10th Floor, Toronto, ON M5V 2T3**
